<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">ChrisKurdziel.com</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2014-04-04T11:03:52-04:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wireframing for Noobs (MBAs too!)]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-wireframing-for-noobs-mbas-too/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-wireframing-for-noobs-mbas-too</id>
  <published>2013-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2013-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the longstanding jokes in business school is that MBAs think in PowerPoint. In the startup world, people don&amp;#8217;t often think in PowerPoint - they think in code.  So what&amp;#8217;s the easiest way to bridge that gap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t try and be something you&amp;#8217;re not (unless you actually want to learn how to code). Instead, use the skills you have/are good at and put them to good use. Think you&amp;#8217;ve got a great idea for a product but can&amp;#8217;t build it with code? Build it with PowerPoint or Keynote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clickable prototypes save a ton of time in the design process and you can get your ideas in front of people quickly to test whether or not they&amp;#8217;re valid. Keynote works on iPads too, so if you&amp;#8217;re looking to build a mobile app, you can do it in Keynote AND test it on iPads with real users.  I&amp;#8217;ve been doing this lately and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more excuses. &lt;a href=&quot;http://reecepacheco.com/post/29701849789/the-end-product-and-a-core-part-of-shelbys&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JFBI&lt;/a&gt;, even if it is in Keynote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-wireframing-for-noobs-mbas-too/&quot;&gt;Wireframing for Noobs (MBAs too!)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on April 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[House of Cards: The Content Wars Are A Game of Thrones]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/house-of-cards-the-content-wars-are-a-game-of-thrones/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/house-of-cards-the-content-wars-are-a-game-of-thrones</id>
  <published>2013-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2013-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;House of Cards has gotten a ton of attention lately for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;It&amp;#8217;s an awesome show (though I haven&amp;#8217;t seen it yet)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;All episodes were delivered at the same time (to satisfy binge viewers)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;It&amp;#8217;s another major step for Netflix in delivering unique content to keep viewers locked into their model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is this model smart?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content providers can use exclusive content to be valuable &amp;amp; differentiate themselves from competitors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Netflix has already done this with Lilyhammer.  They&amp;#8217;ve also continued tapping into&lt;span&gt; &quot;binge viewing&quot; behavior in an organized way.  Although it&amp;#8217;s unclear what the biggest benefits of that behavior will be quite yet, they&amp;#8217;re learning something valuable by being a first mover here. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People want access to content without restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and aside from being the only place to access it, Netflix&amp;#8217;s distribution models is working for consumers with a &amp;#8220;watch where you want, when you want&quot; mindset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;What are the downsides of this model?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s really expensive and only works for top-quality content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Because its so expensive to do it this way (and therefore the costs of failure are high), it only works for top caliber content and therefore isn&amp;#8217;t something that will be the only way things are done. It&amp;#8217;s why &amp;#8220;pilots&quot; exist in TV - see if the audience likes it and then sink more money into it. Episodic content that follows this model also has a benefit of giving viewers a reason to come back to a service. In that sense I think we&amp;#8217;ll see these models mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Piracy is still going to be a big issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; If you don&amp;#8217;t subscribe to Netflix or the service, there&amp;#8217;s no way to get the content except pirating it. That&amp;#8217;s part of the reason Game of Thrones was pirated a ton (and consequently was so successful). Many of the dynamics in &lt;a href=&quot;http://liisten.com/strategy-for-releasing-music-online&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; on the music industry could also apply to video content. We still haven&amp;#8217;t seen a producer of content fully embrace the piracy engine to positive effect yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does this all mean for the people playing this &amp;#8220;game of thrones&quot; in the content landscape?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The implications of all of this are good for startups - Americans watch over 5 hours a day of content and not all of it is that &amp;#8220;top notch&quot; stuff like House of Cards or Game of Thrones. Startups don&amp;#8217;t need to unseat that &amp;#8220;top value&quot; content quite yet - they can let this game of thrones happen and focus more on the Torso of TV (&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/06/the-power-of-torso-tv-why-media-is-racing-to-the-middle/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read Suster&amp;#8217;s post if you haven&amp;#8217;t&lt;/a&gt;) and create a ton of value around providing meaningful context and discovery for the rest of the video landscape.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/house-of-cards-the-content-wars-are-a-game-of-thrones/&quot;&gt;House of Cards: The Content Wars Are A Game of Thrones&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on April 02, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Killing Google Reader]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-killing-google-reader/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-killing-google-reader</id>
  <published>2013-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2013-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced they&amp;#8217;re killing Reader&lt;/a&gt;, one of their most beloved (if my Twitter stream is to be believed) products in their portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a few different apps/sites to keep up with the news. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google Reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reeder (Google Reader interface for iOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instapaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News.Me Daily Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techmeme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacker News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use each of these services for different reasons, and though I&amp;#8217;ve developed a pretty good flow of how they each fit into my day, I&amp;#8217;ve been longing for a better solution. I really wish that there was a product that tied these things together in one or two apps. What would that product look like? Here&amp;#8217;s a quick stab and what I&amp;#8217;d love to see for my two common use cases (daily &amp;#8220;must reads&quot; &amp;amp; weekly &amp;#8220;discovery&quot; reading):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Must Read: My Daily Use Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep/read a curated list of the stuff I absolutely want to see on a regular basis anytime there are updates. This is the stuff I want to read no matter what and it&amp;#8217;s mostly blogs of people who I engage with on a regular basis. (It&amp;#8217;s what Google Reader became for me.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give me an idea of top posts in my social network. The news.me email from the Digg team does a good job of giving me stuff that I may have missed or not seen that&amp;#8217;s highly relevant. Generally only 3-5 of these articles are really necessary to get an idea of what&amp;#8217;s relevant in my network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there isn&amp;#8217;t enough content on a daily basis, then don&amp;#8217;t show me more. Let me get a few minutes of my day back.  This is a problem a lot of apps don&amp;#8217;t consider because they&amp;#8217;re looking for more engagement (which often times = shoving more content in front of you).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover: My Weekly/When I Have Time Use Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once I&amp;#8217;m done with the daily read, open the floodgates and give me some variety. This could be seeded with content, topics and things I&amp;#8217;ve shown an interest in (like Zite) or it could be powered by people I&amp;#8217;m connected to socially. Ideally it&amp;#8217;s a mix of all of the above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I&amp;#8217;ve saved articles for later, show me these articles before letting me run wild exploring the ends of the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hard part here is figuring out how to combine these use cases in an app. Part of the power is in keeping them separate: the problem with apps like Zite is that I never know if I missed an article from a &amp;#8220;must read&quot; site and I don&amp;#8217;t have an interest in discovering new tangental content unless I&amp;#8217;ve finished the stuff that I know is relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the big problems with these weekly apps is that I often forget to go back to them on a regular basis, and they often have content in them that I&amp;#8217;ve already seen or seen elsewhere.  There&amp;#8217;s a strong case for a reading app that unifies these two use cases or at least is aware of what&amp;#8217;s been consumed in the other app so that the probability of duplicates is reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closest thing I&amp;#8217;ve found to this approach is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedafever.com/&quot;&gt;Fever&lt;/a&gt;. It combines &amp;#8220;kindling&quot; (your daily must-reads) with &amp;#8220;sparks&quot; (the rest of the content you are interested in) to give you a smart reading experience.  The only problem? No iOS apps and it&amp;#8217;s self-hosted. :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone else have other ideas out there? Seems that there are a ton of companies tackling this problem but no one has really hit the nail on the head yet (for me).  I&amp;#8217;ve tried Prismatic and while I think the content it surfaces is pretty solid, I find the UX, scrolling and lack of Instapaper support absolutely maddening. Hopefully &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.digg.com/post/45355701332/were-building-a-reader&quot;&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; (or someone else) does it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I also realize this problem is completely non-trivial to solve, that my usage pattern is probably pretty niche and that this is not something I can really pretend to solve in a blog post. Flame away. :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-killing-google-reader/&quot;&gt;Killing Google Reader&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on March 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on Mailbox]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-thoughts-on-mailbox/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-thoughts-on-mailbox</id>
  <published>2013-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/ea130ea588877bbca37dac8458fa7be2/tumblr_inline_mi844pJWBL1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Over the past week I&amp;#8217;ve been playing with Mailbox, so I figured it might be a good candidate for my first product review on product thursday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main assumption behind Mailbox is that most people tend to view their inbox as a to-do list.  Though I&amp;#8217;ve tried to shed that assumption in my own use of Gmail, it&amp;#8217;s been hard. Mailbox is a welcome addition and really reduces the need for me to spend time on actively managing an inbox of actionable email.  Every part of the app is designed to get you to inbox zero, so those who want more functionality in their email might feel a bit limited, but Mailbox is awesome for staying on top of email and following up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of my favorite details in the app (barring the obvious ones)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you&amp;#8217;ve cleared your inbox each day, you get a beautiful, relaxing image that is different every day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;#8217;s a nice little touch that feels like a little &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;reward&quot; each time you hit inbox zero.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing send-from address popup is easier to use than Apple Mail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;#8217;s a list of email addresses to pick from that requires a simple tap instead of a swipe and a tap like Apple&amp;#8217;s wheel selector does. I imagine Apple&amp;#8217;s solution works better for those who have a ton of addresses, but I only have 3 I actively check so it&amp;#8217;s a nice change.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threading of messages is handled really elegantly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Gone are the days of tapping into a thread on Apple Mail and then choosing which message you want to see. Instead, messages all load inline and appear collapsed and greyed out if they&amp;#8217;re already read (much like Gmail&amp;#8217;s web interface)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inline/focused replies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;  I find the design of the reply/new message box to be limiting in a really good way.  Because the box doesn&amp;#8217;t give me the entire screen to write a lengthy response, my emails are becoming shorter and more to the point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tasteful use of gestures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;#8217;s a lot of debate about whether or not Clear&amp;#8217;s UX is ideal, but I love it.  Mailbox&amp;#8217;s gestures are built around very quick/easy actions for each email: archive (short swipe right), view later (short swipe left), add to list (long swipe left), and delete (long swipe right).  These have been really easy to pick up and the UI does a great job of making sure you don&amp;#8217;t make any mistakes and accidentally delete things when you wanted to archive them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And my least favorite parts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t change reply-from address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; like you can in Apple Mail (I do this a lot for mail that people send to my Cornell or Shelby addresses that I want to be directed to my Gmail account).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No easy way to find/search filters in Gmail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; At this point I don&amp;#8217;t really find myself missing this a ton, but it&amp;#8217;d be a nice to have.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push notifications are a bit wonky.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; If you have filters in Gmail which are set up to move mail out of your inbox, Mailbox may still badge the app that you have mail. This &amp;#8220;false positive&quot; can be a little frustrating especially if you&amp;#8217;re compulsive about keeping notifications to a minimum on iOS, but I imagine it will get better with time. This is likely one of the reasons they&amp;#8217;re letting people into the app on a rolling basis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No iPad experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Desktop Gmail works pretty well in conjunction with Mailbox, but I&amp;#8217;ve found managing email on my iPad just isn&amp;#8217;t fun anymore. Gimme that iPad app!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;#8217;s about it - not sure how helpful/comprehensive this review is, but hopefully it&amp;#8217;s useful to those that are wondering whether Mailbox is worth the wait (I think it is)!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-thoughts-on-mailbox/&quot;&gt;Thoughts on Mailbox&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on February 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minimum Viable Design]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-minimum-viable-design/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-minimum-viable-design</id>
  <published>2013-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lots of startups (especially those in NYC) spend a ton of time on visual design and making sure that the look and feel of their product is close to perfect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While my obsessive tendencies often encourage me to consider every design option presented, I&amp;#8217;ve had to remember that too much attention to design can often get in the way of moving a product forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re a startup trying to iterate quickly, understand your customer base and think about things as an MVP, there are times when it&amp;#8217;s smart to eschew design for shipping product (provided it doesn&amp;#8217;t cripple functionality). That extra bit of design/attention to detail can be helpful, for sure, but a good product person should understand when that matters and when it doesn&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/a23b6d525e8c82a422ac8ef96dfc05c7/tumblr_inline_mi0rezkXtc1qz4rgp.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-minimum-viable-design/&quot;&gt;Minimum Viable Design&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on February 07, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA["WTF is UX?"]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-wtf-is-ux/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-wtf-is-ux</id>
  <published>2013-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/a0896f633e9517394d056d493453124d/tumblr_inline_mhiaoj0usO1qz4rgp.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a great post about UX on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcodesign.com/1671735/infographic-the-intricate-anatomy-of-ux-design&quot;&gt;Fast.co Design&lt;/a&gt; today and it includes the infographic above. The overall point is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To think any designer could be an expert in each of these circles is sheer absurdity, but to recognize that &lt;strong&gt;every end user is an expert&lt;/strong&gt; in each of these circles is highly important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I&amp;#8217;d worked alongside product teams before entering the New York startup community, I&amp;#8217;m not ashamed to admit that I never really heard the term &amp;#8220;UX&quot; used much. I could probably crack a joke about how that&amp;#8217;s unexpected for people who work in big companies that develop enterprise healthcare IT applications, but I&amp;#8217;ll refrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a bit of a n00b on the design front, it took me a while to appreciate the subtleties of these different areas of design. Depending on what you&amp;#8217;re building, each area has a different level of importance, but together they all form something that&amp;#8217;s the cornerstone of your product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While there are many days when I wish I had more formal education on the tenets of good user experience or interaction design, I think it&amp;#8217;s good to remember that no matter how much formal education we have, user experience comes down to putting yourself in the shoes of others &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;and asking &amp;#8220;does this work for me?&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This empathetic approach can be helpful in UX decision-making, but it&amp;#8217;s also a characteristic that increases chances of success in the customer support experience and in service industries. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not saying that one has to be empathetic with the customer/user because they&amp;#8217;re always right. On the contrary, the customer may be wrong (and angry!), but their perspective is valid and should be used to gain insight and understanding around the experience. Ultimately, it&amp;#8217;s up to the &amp;#8220;UX&quot; person to translate that perspective into something that is actionable/productive for all parties involved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-wtf-is-ux/&quot;&gt;"WTF is UX?"&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on January 31, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing with Emotion]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-designing-with-emotion/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-designing-with-emotion</id>
  <published>2013-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/2a55e6fa1b9395b1b7bc6965913e72e7/tumblr_inline_mh5amt0xXq1qaedq5.jpg&quot;/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1937557006/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1937557006&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=chriskurdziel-20&quot;&gt;Designing for Emotion&lt;/a&gt;, which contains a number of interesting examples about how design can be used to evoke emotion. &lt;span&gt;There are a few cool examples in the book, but the one that stood out to me most was Apple&amp;#8217;s implementation of their blinking sleep status indicator. This has been documented before (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freepatentsonline.com/6658577.html&quot;&gt;and patented back in 2002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;), but if anyone has wondered why their Macbook&amp;#8217;s sleep indicator was strangely comforting it&amp;#8217;s because the pulsating rhythm is based on the respiratory rate of a human (12-20 cycles per minute).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At Shelby, one of our core values is &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be human&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot; - this applies in the way we carry ourselves in the larger startup community, internally with our team and also in the way we approach building product.  This is a product philosophy that I&amp;#8217;m increasingly taking to heart and one that I think has to be at the center of transformative technology products in slower-moving, low-tech industries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Take healthcare, for example. There are a ton of technology companies building solutions for the healthcare enterprise (I used to work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mckesson.com&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt;), but most are just focused on performing a specific task and not providing enjoyable UX. As Aaron Walter says in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1937557006/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1937557006&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=chriskurdziel-20&quot;&gt;Designing for Emotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &amp;#8220;certainly we all want to eat edible foods with nutritional value, but we also crave &lt;em&gt;flavor&lt;/em&gt;.&quot; Based on my experience, design of healthcare IT systems has been focused on making products that are &amp;#8220;edible&quot; - they get the job done but they&amp;#8217;re pretty crappy in terms of creating an experience that physicians feel they can&amp;#8217;t live without.  It&amp;#8217;s no surprise to see that adoption of healthcare tech &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationweek.com/healthcare/electronic-medical-records/ehr-adoption-us-remains-the-slow-poke/240142152&quot;&gt;is slow&lt;/a&gt;. I believe there&amp;#8217;s a huge opportunity for better, more human design to help speed the adoption of healthcare tech among a physician population that is short on time and patience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Anyone else have other examples of industries waiting to be transformed by designing with emotion?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/product-thursday-designing-with-emotion/&quot;&gt;Designing with Emotion&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Product Thursdays]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/introducing-product-thursdays/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/introducing-product-thursdays</id>
  <published>2013-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ever since I was a kid, I spent hours clicking around on computers, obsessed with learning the ins and outs of whatever OS, application, or web product I discovered at the time. I remember when I got my first Windows laptop after years of using a Mac, I explored every little system setting and tweaked ini files so I could get an experience that was exactly what I wanted. Over time, this obsession with technology guided me to study CS in college and subsequently work in tech.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I have experience interacting with consumers (at &lt;a href=&quot;http://shelby.tv&quot;&gt;Shelby&lt;/a&gt;) and businesses (at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mckesson.com&quot;&gt;McKesson&lt;/a&gt;) using vastly different kinds of tech products, I have relatively modest training (other than my hands-on experience) on the fundamentals that inform great product design and the process required to effectively manage larger product teams.  In my effort to become more well-versed in the history and community of the product, I thought I&amp;#8217;d start a weekly post on product to share my findings with the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus begins Product Thursdays. If there&amp;#8217;s stuff you&amp;#8217;d love to see, drop me an &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ckurdziel+product@gmail.com&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; with a suggestion!  Otherwise, here&amp;#8217;s a list of where I&amp;#8217;ll probably head with this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Resources&lt;/strong&gt; - What are some great sources for learning/self-study about product design?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Process&lt;/strong&gt; - What companies are known for building awesome products and how do they do it?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Examples&lt;/strong&gt; - What are the best examples of products that I&amp;#8217;m currently enjoying and why do I think they&amp;#8217;re awesome? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/introducing-product-thursdays/&quot;&gt;Product Thursdays&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on January 17, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Comes The Dream]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/first-comes-the-dream/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/first-comes-the-dream</id>
  <published>2012-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last &lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/what-was-it/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thursday night&lt;/a&gt; I had the incredible opportunity to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neil_deGrasse_Tyson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neil DeGrasse Tyson&lt;/a&gt; speak at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.haydenplanetarium.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hayden planetarium&lt;/a&gt; here in New York about brining STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering &amp;amp; Math) to more people and making it a deeper part of our culture. The theme of the event was &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5927637/first-comes-the-dream-at-the-american-museum-of-natural-history-an-evening-of-innovation-and-imagination&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;First Comes the Dream&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;253&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/cXzH5reZRHk&quot; width=&quot;450&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite comments of the night was when Neil remarked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;the extent to which entertainment reaches for the lowest mental acuity is an indication we are not reaching high enough.&quot;  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil went on to advocate for pop culture as an effective tool to bring people into real education and I got to thinking about how this dovetails pretty nicely with some of our goals at Shelby.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe in the power of the internet to surface content that &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; reach high enough (in part because discovery driven by the user). While a video of a wolf playing with a bear might just be written off as cute to some, it can also act as inspiration for those that want to understand more than they see in the video. When such a video is presented in a collection of video about nature and science, it acts as an entry point that then engages the viewer in something more meaningful for the rest of their viewing session.  In addition, the experience of Internet video is not just about the content itself - it&amp;#8217;s also about the community and discussion that happens around this video and engages people even more (I&amp;#8217;m looking at you, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://shelby.tv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shelby&lt;/a&gt; is not (yet) building a spacecraft that will take us on manned missions to Mars, we are really focused on helping everyone (not just the tech enabled) find and engage with the video that tickles the brain more than the average bit of network TV.  I&amp;#8217;m excited to keep after that vision with Reece and Dan and I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to seeing the new Shelby unleashed upon the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full video of Neil&amp;#8217;s talk, check out the embed at the top of this post. Thanks to the awesome crew at Brew PR and Gizmodo for helping put this event together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7fvhxmCOM1qamfj2o1_500.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/first-comes-the-dream/&quot;&gt;First Comes The Dream&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on July 23, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Silicon Valley Doesn't Have to be Wall Street]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley-doesnt-have-to-be-wall-street/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley-doesnt-have-to-be-wall-street</id>
  <published>2012-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The tech industry originally made its name by being different than Wall Street - it&amp;#8217;s a place where people can make money but simultaneously eschew the conventions of dress code and corporatism in favor of something more grand &amp;#8212; the chance to change an industry (or dare I say, even the world).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/06/what-happened-to-silicon-values/258905/&quot;&gt;article about how Silicon Valley has betrayed some of the traditional values that made it great&lt;/a&gt;. In the article, Bill Davidow argues, &amp;#8220;the valley is no longer as concerned about serving the customer, and even sees great opportunity in exploitation. We are beginning to act like the bankers who sold subprime mortgages to naïve consumers. In such an environment, we are less likely to create the role models of the past who guided the valley to its future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7bicwi4ZG1qaedq5.jpg&quot;/&gt;This is a pretty controversial statement, but Davidow makes a good point. He goes on to say that &amp;#8220;Lock-in creates dominant players &amp;#8212; witness Google, Facebook, Microsoft. And in this monopoly-driven environment, customers get exploited.&quot; That somewhat true [but overly simplistic] analysis is certainly consistent with sentiment toward Wall Street. Two recent examples of Wall Street&amp;#8217;s attitude towards customers come to mind: the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;gl=us&amp;amp;tbm=nws&amp;amp;q=libor+scandal&amp;amp;oq=libor+scandal&quot;&gt;Libor scandal&lt;/a&gt;, and the recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/07/15/business/goldman-sachs-and-a-sale-gone-horribly-awry.html?_r=2&amp;amp;hpw&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;lawsuit involving Goldman Sachs and Dragon software&lt;/a&gt;. In both cases, bankers are characterized with attitudes of putting their own interests (growth, getting paid, etc.) ahead of those of their customers. &amp;#8220;We guided them to a completed transaction&quot; at first seems like bankers are doing their jobs (technically, they are), but such a mindset is one of the reasons we equate Wall Street banks with &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/the-great-american-bubble-machine-20100405&quot;&gt;blood sucking vampire squids&lt;/a&gt;.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick pivots, data driven decision-making, and Facebook&amp;#8217;s Open Graph can open a world of possibilities among startups. I&amp;#8217;d argue that such tools aren&amp;#8217;t inherently good or evil &amp;#8212; they exist to be used however companies choose to use them. However, the communities we develop with these tools do often end up with a conscience. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/&quot;&gt;Reddit&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; community almost certainly made it a longer term success than &lt;a href=&quot;http://digg.com/&quot;&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt;. Even though it wasn&amp;#8217;t a giant financial outcome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/&quot;&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt; avoided the issues of &lt;a href=&quot;http://digg.com/&quot;&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; (overly rapid growth without proper community) by focusing on the long term and only employing tools for growth when they were right for their community/customers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexisohanian&quot;&gt;Alexis&lt;/a&gt; and Steve were comfortable with an exit that allowed them to keep building and preserved the longer term vision of what Reddit was about. In the end, they&amp;#8217;re the ones bigger than ever, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2012/07/12/digg-sold-to-linkedin-and-the-washington-post-and-betaworks/&quot;&gt;Digg just got sold in a firesale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Facebook&amp;#8217;s Open Graph: &lt;a href=&quot;http://socialcam.com/&quot;&gt;Socialcam&lt;/a&gt; was able to leverage the open graph to snatch the #1 Facebook application spot in just a few short months. Traffic has supposedly plateaued recently and some even indicate that &lt;a href=&quot;http://appdata.com/apps/facebook/150768931647055-socialcam&quot;&gt;usage of the app is down&lt;/a&gt;. Today, news hit the wire that &lt;a href=&quot;http://allthingsd.com/20120717/autodesk-buys-mobile-video-shooting-star-socialcam-for-60m/&quot;&gt;Socialcam sold for $60M to Autocad&lt;/a&gt;. While this outcome appears to be tremendous for the founders and early investors in Socialcam (congrats to all of them), many will infer that this exit was almost entirely predicated on the large user base Socialcam was able to attract using the Open Graph. A number of founders will now to look to Open Graph not as a way to connect with the *right* users in a way that is meaningful, but rather as a tool that might help them flip their company for a big payday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;left&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7bidbuVx01qaedq5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot;/&gt;When too many high profile companies use tools like data, the Open Graph, or others to extract value from customers at the expense of building lasting value, we cheapen the value proposition of the tech industry as a whole (especially relative to finance). Now, more than ever, it&amp;#8217;s important for us to set the example in tech of how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Responsible-Company-Yvon-Chouinard/dp/0980122783&quot;&gt;companies can be responsible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a VC, I can imagine it is difficult to balance the need to return your investors&amp;#8217; capital in a relatively short timeframe with the fact that may be at odds with what is right for the business in the long term. Similarly, as a founder, it&amp;#8217;s probably easy to go for use number growth at the expense of real community/engagement to generate hype and valuation bumps faster than the competition.&lt;strong&gt; Sure, it may net you a quick exit and create an illusion of value, but it&amp;#8217;s not something that benefits people outside the tech ecosystem in the long term. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isn&amp;#8217;t that why so many of us &amp;#8220;dreamers and doers&quot; are here to begin with?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m7bic3mG4y1qaedq5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/silicon-valley-doesnt-have-to-be-wall-street/&quot;&gt;Silicon Valley Doesn't Have to be Wall Street&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on July 17, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The oral history of Silicon Valley VCs]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-oral-history-of-silicon-valley-vcs/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-oral-history-of-silicon-valley-vcs</id>
  <published>2012-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zdanielshi&quot;&gt;friend of mine&lt;/a&gt; recently discovered &lt;a href=&quot;http://bancroft.berkeley.edu/ROHO/projects/vc/transcripts.html&quot;&gt;this archive&lt;/a&gt; of interview transcripts of many of Silicon Valley&amp;#8217;s seminal venture capitalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering most of the guys on this list started their respective firms before the widespread adoption of the internet, I think it&amp;#8217;s pretty cool to think about how this stuff was documented. In many cases, some of the details are much more intimate as a result of being recounted in a more informal fashion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don Valentine (founder of Sequoia Capital) doesn&amp;#8217;t keep a blog or have a Facebook page, but he did sit down and &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalassets.lib.berkeley.edu/roho/ucb/text/valentine_donald.pdf&quot;&gt;orally recount much of his history&lt;/a&gt;, which is documented in these archives.  It&amp;#8217;s a fascinating read (both from a personal and a professional perspective) if you have the time to look through some of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a fun excerpt from his interview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valentine: I don’t believe in business school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hughes: Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valentine: We have people here at Sequoia who went to business school, but most of the primary partners here have not gone to business school. Or said differently, and this is a true story, when asked where I went to business school, I said, “Fairchild Semiconductor.” And the people said, “We’ve never heard of it.” I was talking to people who thought that if you didn’t go to Harvard Business School you could never learn how to manage money. And my rejoinder was I was not interested in learning how to raise money; I was interested in building great companies, and I didn’t have to go Harvard Business School to build great companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the full archives of interviews &lt;a href=&quot;http://bancroft.berkeley.edu/ROHO/projects/vc/transcripts.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-oral-history-of-silicon-valley-vcs/&quot;&gt;The oral history of Silicon Valley VCs&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on April 22, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare is a long slog but I think it's worth it.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/healthcare-is-a-long-slog-but-i-think-its-worth-it/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/healthcare-is-a-long-slog-but-i-think-its-worth-it</id>
  <published>2012-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m2cis49k7f1qaedq5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;A few weeks ago, I had the pleasure of attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://blueprinthealth.org&quot;&gt;Blueprint Health&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s inaugural demo day here in New York.  For the unititiated, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blueprinthealth.org&quot;&gt;Blueprint&lt;/a&gt; is an accelerator and member of the Techstars network specifically focused on healthcare startups. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/sladenyc&quot;&gt;Mat&lt;/a&gt; and Brad are great guys and really invested in the success of Blueprint and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blueprinthealth.org/index.php?page=companies&quot;&gt;companies&lt;/a&gt; they mentor.  Healthcare startups outside of the quantified self movement haven&amp;#8217;t really been in the limelight (as far as I can tell) so I was blown away away when I got to the Blueprint offices and was greeted by a packed house and tons of investors that traditionally focus on the consumer internet space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;I have a feeling we&amp;#8217;re only seeing the beginning of innovation within healthcare. There&amp;#8217;s an incredible amount of opportunity in this space and I hope that the entrepreneurs who face this tough road are courageous enough to keep trudging along even in spite of the fact that it&amp;#8217;s a difficult space to work in. The long sales cycles, physician adoption challenges and a host of other things are enough to frustrate someone who expects the pace of innovation in healthcare to mirror that of consumer web services.  In a world where super fast $1B sorts of outsized returns dominate headlines (oh hey Instagram!), it&amp;#8217;s understandably a tough thing to stay focused on a business that might be a &amp;#8220;grind&quot; over the long haul.  In light of this recent news about Instagram, I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a lot about how the current consumer internet landscape can relate to other verticals (in addition to the impact it will have on them).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Dennis Crowley worked on Dodgeball and has been thinking about location for most of his career - he started thinking about this problem a while ago but it has only been recently (in the past few years) that he and his team have been able to really bring their solution to the masses. This example is one that is relevant to healthcare, I think. I hope we&amp;#8217;ll see more young entrepreneurs take a crack at problems in healthcare and even if their first companies fail, they&amp;#8217;ll keep working on effecting change in the space.  These are the entreprneuers I want to work with and I&amp;#8217;m really excited that others like Brad and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/sladenyc&quot;&gt;Mat&lt;/a&gt; at Blueprint Health have committed to working with them over the long haul as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Because of the nature of incumbents, regulation and other factors, it&amp;#8217;s unclear whether or not we&amp;#8217;ll see a Google or Facebook sized exit in the heathcare IT world.  However, I am hopeful that we&amp;#8217;ll see a a number of companies have a big impact, help cut a ton of waste and save millions of lives in the process. I hope that there are a bunch of entrepreneurs willing to &amp;#8220;go for it&quot; and endure the pain of the process in the hopes of changing the industry.  And &lt;strong&gt;I hope that there are also investors out there who are willing to weather the storm and back the entrepreneurs who may be a bit idealistic now but who have the fresh perspective necessary to succeed in the face of the challenges we face in the long term. Their first idea may not be a huge hit, but the next few very well might.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS - I realize it might seem hypocritical that I&amp;#8217;m writing this post as someone working for a consumer Internet company. While that is a fair point, I&amp;#8217;m still involved in healthcare on a number of fronts and I strongly believe that experience in a consumer oriented internet company coupled with my healthcare background can actually help me provide perspective in healthcare that is unique (hence this blog post). Right now, though, my skill set is best served with the greatest team in NYC building an awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://shelby.tv&quot;&gt;product&lt;/a&gt; that I love. :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/healthcare-is-a-long-slog-but-i-think-its-worth-it/&quot;&gt;Healthcare is a long slog but I think it's worth it.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on April 13, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[FAKEGRIMLOCK is a pretty cool dude.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/fakegrimlock-is-a-pretty-cool-dude/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/fakegrimlock-is-a-pretty-cool-dude</id>
  <published>2012-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m1xqwgaa1Q1qaedq5.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the real @&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/fakegrimlock&quot;&gt;FAKEGRIMLOCK&lt;/a&gt; sat down with &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenextweb.com/insider/2012/03/31/breakfast-of-champions-meet-the-man-known-as-fakegrimlock/&quot;&gt;The Next Web to talk&lt;/a&gt; about why he does what he does:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;It’s a proof of concept, it’s to prove a theory. And it’s to prove that who you are doesn’t matter. In fact, truth requires that you aren’t anyone, because if you’re someone, whatever you say is always biased. It’s influenced by what you know about that person&amp;#8230;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&amp;#8230;So the reason I have to be just a character is that there is no anything else. The words are just the words. And the words are funny and they are ridiculous, but they’re true. And the ridiculousness is to disarm you, so you forget even further. Forget what’s wrapped around it, forget your preconceived notions, forget what you think is going on, just listen to the words. Because I very, very purposefully craft those words to be hard to understand because I want you to stop and think about them. And by stopping and thinking about them, they get past all these filters. I’m completely hacking the social channel that we all rely on.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s great to see another pseudonym garner some serious attention from the press and so succinctly explain why he has chosen to remain anonymous.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christopher_Poole&quot;&gt;moot&lt;/a&gt; has some great thoughts on the importance of supporting pseudonyms and anonymity within internet services.  I agree with him that providing the option for pseudonyms can really help make the internet a more powerful tool for expression. If you haven&amp;#8217;t seen moot talk about this sort of stuff, here&amp;#8217;s a great primer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/e3Zs74IH0mc&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few people have heard that I was lucky enough to have beers with The Grimster down at SXSW and chat about what he&amp;#8217;s up to IRL.  Many have asked me about what the &amp;#8220;real&quot; GRIMLOCK is like. Honestly, I have to say that he didn&amp;#8217;t reveal too much more than he has revealed to his fanbase online.  He could be a super famous VC/entrepreneur, a serial killer, a concert pianist, or just a regular dude (I have no idea).  To moot&amp;#8217;s point in the video above, I don&amp;#8217;t think much of that is really the point (well&amp;#8230;maybe the serial killer bit does&amp;#8230;). We just have to laugh and enjoy how FAKEGRIMLOCK chooses to express himself&amp;#8230; OR ELSE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more FAKEGRIMLOCK goodness, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://projectgoats.com&quot;&gt;projectGOATS.com&lt;/a&gt; for some great interviews. And moot, if you read this, I think it would be awesome for you to interview FAKEGRIMLOCK&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/fakegrimlock-is-a-pretty-cool-dude/&quot;&gt;FAKEGRIMLOCK is a pretty cool dude.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on April 04, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Honoring the Past]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/honoring-the-past/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/honoring-the-past</id>
  <published>2012-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  <updated>2012-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was driving to NYC with my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.punylittlehuman.com/&quot;&gt;Daniel&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blueprinthealth.org/&quot;&gt;Blueprint Health Demo Day&lt;/a&gt; and as usual, we spent most of the car ride discussing VC and the startup ecosystem.  Every time I travel with Daniel, he knocks me over the head with some amazing story about the rich history of the VC community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;#8217;s moment was regarding the origin of the limited partnership in VC. Essentially, a limited partnership was supposed first used by Bill Elfers when he left &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Research_and_Development_Corporation&quot;&gt;American Research and Development Corporation&lt;/a&gt; (widely regarded as one of the first VC firms and an investor in Digital Equipment Corporation) to found &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greylock_Partners&quot;&gt;Greylock Partners&lt;/a&gt; in 1965. The limited partnership was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scaruffi.com/svhistory/sv/chap78.html&quot;&gt;supposedly something Elfers had seen&lt;/a&gt; during his days in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wildcatter&quot;&gt;oil wildcatting business&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stories like these may not fundamentally change my outlook on limited partnerships or their use in VC, but they provide color and richness to many aspects of a business that are taken for granted. What&amp;#8217;s particularly interesting about these sorts of stories is that much of the startup ecosystem is so focused on the present and the future, rather than the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure why this is, but as a whole I think we need to spend more time making sense of and honoring the history of our community.  Real-time data feeds and the next big thing are great, but there&amp;#8217;s so much that entrepreneurs, VCs, and even users can understand and learn from those that have come before us.  I love seeing startups like &lt;a href=&quot;http://timehop.com/&quot;&gt;Timehop&lt;/a&gt; that are focused on collecting and organizing this historical data. Whether it&amp;#8217;s through design approach, focus on historical data, or just through decision-making, I really hope we&amp;#8217;ll see more startups show reverence to past.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/honoring-the-past/&quot;&gt;Honoring the Past&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on March 29, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saying "No" Sucks]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/saying-no-sucks/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/saying-no-sucks</id>
  <published>2012-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2012-02-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had coffee with an awesome entrepreneur over the weekend and he said something that really got me thinking: &amp;#8220;I hate hearing no.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out that I hate &lt;em&gt;saying&lt;/em&gt; no (and this can sometimes get me in trouble). I love the feeling of being a &amp;#8220;yes&quot; man, having a can do attitude, and making things happen that seem like they&amp;#8217;re not possible, but sometimes there&amp;#8217;s a real cost associated with saying &amp;#8220;yes.&quot;  Business school has taught me a number of things, but one the most important lessons has been how to say &amp;#8220;no&quot; when it&amp;#8217;s appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;#8217;ve had to deliver bad news entrepreneurs we can&amp;#8217;t invest in, tell people I can&amp;#8217;t carve out time for a meeting because I can&amp;#8217;t be in multiple places at multiple times, and say no to extra work because I can&amp;#8217;t quite get it all done. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has been pretty frustrating, but ultimately, I think saying no to some things just means you can say yes to others. I&amp;#8217;m not talking about that &amp;#8220;kinda-sorta&quot; yes that&amp;#8217;s driven by FOMO (fear of missing out), dilutes your focus, leads to flaky scheduling and spreads you thin. Giving someone or something a real &amp;#8220;yes&quot; and committing to that yes means you can devote yourself to that thing and accomplish it well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, I think this boils down to one thing: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;being present&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Pick the things in life that really matter: your family, your friends, the people, work and art that truly inspires you. You don&amp;#8217;t have to ignore everything else, but don&amp;#8217;t say yes to anything that compromises the level of enjoyment or excellence that you get and give to those things that really matter.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/saying-no-sucks/&quot;&gt;Saying "No" Sucks&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on February 27, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building Community]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/building-community/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/building-community</id>
  <published>2012-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2012-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;YouTube recently released stats that &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtube-global.blogspot.com/2012/01/holy-nyans-60-hours-per-minute-and-4.html&quot;&gt;60+ hours of content are being uploaded to their site per minute&lt;/a&gt;. That sort of data is pretty impressive, but when you take a look at a lot of that content, it becomes a little less impressive. I&amp;#8217;ve noticed an increasing amount of video responses to popular videos on YouTube that feature women with low cut shirts in the thumbnails blathering on about whatever video they&amp;#8217;re responding to. This sort of content is not exactly enhancing the community at YouTube, so I can only assume these types of people are trying to cash in on ad revenue via traffic from the videos they&amp;#8217;re responding to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Linkbait is nothing new and I&amp;#8217;m not the only one who has noticed this, but I was recently reminded of all this because of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XJHzbXEc2so&quot;&gt;video from reddit&lt;/a&gt; the other day. This guy isn&amp;#8217;t the most articulate speaker, but he makes his point pretty well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;Problems like this one indicate that communities and curation have become increasingly important in the online world. At &lt;a href=&quot;http://Shelby.tv/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Shelby.tv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, as we think about the future of what video community should look like, we are building the type of community that doesn&amp;#8217;t promote the &amp;#8220;spammy&quot; user-generated-content (UGC) that we see on places like YouTube. Recommendations and organic UGC are great, but recommendations (especially as related to the long tail of UGC) powered without a social filter or strong context around them feel empty, spammy and often result in the lower quality kind of stuff I&amp;#8217;m referring to here.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;We believe the social filter is the key to building a community of content that doesn&amp;#8217;t promote this sort of abusive behavior and we&amp;#8217;re really excited about sharing what we&amp;#8217;re building with the rest of the world.  More on this soon. ;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/building-community/&quot;&gt;Building Community&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on February 25, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How should startups approach CES?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/how-should-startups-approach-ces/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/how-should-startups-approach-ces</id>
  <published>2012-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2012-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;I (and the rest of team Shelby) recently attended CES, the largest consumer electronics show in the world.  It was my first time going to such a huge event, so consequently, it was also my first time navigating the waters of a trade show that is largely geared toward large companies rather than small startups. In an effort to make things more accessible to the startups interested in attending CES in the future, I thought &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;I&amp;#8217;d share some of the questions I had as we planned for CES&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do we need to have a booth at CES?  &lt;/strong&gt;Depends on what your goals &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;are&amp;#8212;the&lt;/span&gt; booth was useful for us because we are a consumer web startup and need to be visible. Not only did we attract investors and potential business partners, but we attracted users and were able to test different aspects of our pitch on them. In this sense, the booth was &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;invaluable.&lt;/span&gt; If you&amp;#8217;re not a &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;consumer-facing&lt;/span&gt; startup and are on a tight budget, a booth may not be worth it (unless you can get it for free like we did). You&amp;#8217;re still better off with some kind of meeting place to gather at (could be a hotel room) and schedule BD meetings for, and you&amp;#8217;ll have to get more creative about how you generate awareness around your startup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much money do we need? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;Cost&lt;/span&gt; can vary greatly between companies, &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;so it&amp;#8217;s hard to provide a straight answer on this one&lt;/span&gt;. If you&amp;#8217;re a small startup under 10 employees and on a tight budget, it&amp;#8217;s possible to scrap together stuff pretty cheaply.  The biggest expenses will be airfare, &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;hotel, and&lt;/span&gt; official CES expenses (booth &amp;amp; press events if you choose to get pay for these).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What sort of stuff should we pay &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;for, and what should&lt;/span&gt; we try to get for free? How does a startup get the most ROI for the least cost at an event where many of the vendors have deep pockets?  &lt;/strong&gt;Staying close to the action was really important to us. &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;If&lt;/span&gt; you&amp;#8217;re planning on taking &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;meetings&lt;/span&gt;, the right hotel room can also double as &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;space for that; consider &lt;/span&gt;ponying up for the right room.  Almost everything at &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;CES&lt;/span&gt; (from carpet in the booth to press releases through the CEA) costs money. Figure out what your priorities are ahead of time and optimize your spend accordingly.  That said, little things like upgrading to nicer carpet in the booth can make a big difference when you&amp;#8217;re on your feet 16+ hours a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other tips?&lt;/strong&gt; In the weeks prior to CES, schedule the meetings you can for the afternoons to take place in your suite or booth. This timing allows you to hunt down other people during your mornings on the show floor&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;.  Also, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;only send the &lt;/span&gt;number of employees that is right for you&amp;#8212;we found 4 at the booth was pretty ideal. We had at least 2 people pitching at a &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;time,&lt;/span&gt; but the extra two often helped pull in additional onlookers &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;and &lt;/span&gt;generate more buzz around our booth (or were available to go scout other booths).  Our neighbors started coming over to check us out because of the volume of traffic that we attracted &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;as a team&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall recommendation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; be creative! There are a lot of low budget (but interesting) ways to engage people at CES and other trade shows.  This is what being a startup is all about, so be comfortable in your own skin and people will love it!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;p1&quot;&gt;The questions above aren&amp;#8217;t exhaustive, but they&amp;#8217;re pretty representative of the stuff we thought about this year and hopefully will be helpful to startups in the future that attend CES. A lot of people may think CES is a waste of time, and while it might be if you approach it incorrectly, there&amp;#8217;s a lot to be learned and achieved if you approach things with an &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;open, but focused, mind.  More thoughts on how to crush CES?  Leave a comment and I&amp;#8217;ll add to the list!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/how-should-startups-approach-ces/&quot;&gt;How should startups approach CES?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on February 03, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cornell + NYC = awesome sauce]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/cornell--nyc--awesome-sauce/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/cornell--nyc--awesome-sauce</id>
  <published>2011-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2011-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s no secret that Cornell and Stanford are both gunning for NYC&amp;#8217;s applied science and tech campus initiative. I&amp;#8217;m obviously biased here, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.observer.com/2011/11/cornells-the-one-when-it-comes-to-new-yorks-tech-campus/&quot;&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not the only one&lt;/a&gt; who thinks there are a few pretty compelling reasons that Cornell would be the best choice for the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cornell already has an active and engaged alumni base in NYC.&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;#8217;ve got a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; network of alumni (including the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cornellangels.com/&quot;&gt;Cornell Angel Network&lt;/a&gt;) who stay in New York after graduation. Scott Belsky &lt;a href=&quot;http://scottbelsky.tumblr.com/post/11581276875/bringing-tech-talent-to-nyc-cornell&quot;&gt;makes a great point&lt;/a&gt; that a good portion of the existing Cornell network is already in New York and that the network effects of the existing alumni base will KEEP tech talent in NYC over the long term.  I agree.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incredible engineering talent and unique programs.&lt;/strong&gt; MIT and Stanford get a lot of press for their kick-ass engineering programs.  Cornell gets less, but having spent a bunch of time in and around the engineering buildings on campus this fall, I have to say that I&amp;#8217;m blown away by some of the talent here.  The biggest problem is that a lot of the engineering talent isn&amp;#8217;t as aware of what&amp;#8217;s going on in NYC - a campus in NYC would change that.  We&amp;#8217;ve also got some non-traditional curricula like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.human.cornell.edu/fsad/&quot;&gt;Fabric Science&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://foodscience.cornell.edu/&quot;&gt;Food Science&lt;/a&gt; that I think embody the interesting conflux between technology and other industries (such fashion and food) that are part of the New York culture.  Top it off with extracurriculars like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brventurefund.com&quot;&gt;BR Venture Fund&lt;/a&gt;, the business school&amp;#8217;s small $1.5M seed stage venture fund (full disclosure: I&amp;#8217;m one of the lucky MBAs that helps run this fund) and you&amp;#8217;ve got a really unique set of complements to Cornell&amp;#8217;s core engineering program that set it apart from the competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We&amp;#8217;re not already in NYC but are still close by.&lt;/strong&gt; As I&amp;#8217;ve been traveling back and forth between NYC and Ithaca, I&amp;#8217;m slowly coming to the realization that each place has served a distinct purpose in my development over the past year.  This may seem a little counter-intuitive, but the fact that Cornell&amp;#8217;s main campus is not in NYC is a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; thing. Ithaca is a quiet (albeit brutally cold) safe haven from the bustle of the city.  I think there&amp;#8217;s a real benefit to being able to learn in an environment that is solely focused on learning. I also think having a campus in NYC and in Ithaca gives students the opportunity to both focus on real world application of their learning (in NYC) and escape for some more introspective learning (in Ithaca).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re interested in more of Cornell&amp;#8217;s propsal, check out the Cornell in NYC website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cornell.edu/nyc/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and make sure to follow the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/nyctechcampus&quot;&gt;twitter account&lt;/a&gt; for updates as well!  This is a really exciting time for the tech community in NYC and I&amp;#8217;m really excited that Cornell has the opportunity to be a bigger part of it than it already is.  Whether we win the proposal or not, I have no doubt that our alumni will continue to make a dent in the NYC tech scene for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/cornell--nyc--awesome-sauce/&quot;&gt;Cornell + NYC = awesome sauce&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on November 25, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do you sell your corporate experience to a startup?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-sell-your-corporate-experience-to-a-startup/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-sell-your-corporate-experience-to-a-startup</id>
  <published>2011-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2011-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had a few conversations with classmates, prospective MBAs and others looking to get into the startup world lately about making the transition from a big corporation to a small startup.  One of the common questions that comes up is &amp;#8220;how did you sell your corporate experience to a startup?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the underlying assumptions here is that corporate experience isn&amp;#8217;t particularly valuable in the startup world, but I don&amp;#8217;t think that could be farther from the truth.  Here&amp;#8217;s a few reasons why your experience at a big company might actually make you more valuable to a startup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You know how the incumbent works.&lt;/strong&gt; If you&amp;#8217;re looking to join a startup that is disrupting an industry you used to work in, you know what the existing challenges are in that industry.  Long sales cycle? Complicated barriers to entry? Excessive government regulation? User adoption issues? All this stuff is relevant to startups and your experience from the perspective of a big company can be really valuable to a startup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You know what an idea looks like at scale.&lt;/strong&gt; While it&amp;#8217;s certainly awesome to work for a startup because startups are agile, startups want to be successful. With that success comes scale, and if you&amp;#8217;re someone that knows what works and what doesn&amp;#8217;t at scale, you can add a ton of value. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You might be the only one with corporate experience.&lt;/strong&gt;  A lot of young tech entrepreneurs have been building businesses for their entire professional careers and thus may not have experience in a big company.  Guess what that means? You can think differently and that&amp;#8217;s a GOOD thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are probably a bunch of items I&amp;#8217;m missing here, but I think the real point is ultimately this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you really want to work at a startup and identify with the product and the vision, your experience is only as relevant as you make it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any experience is better than no experience, so get out there and do stuff! Then figure out what makes you unique and sell that to the founders.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think about making the transition from a big company to a startup?  I&amp;#8217;d love to hear your thoughts in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/how-do-you-sell-your-corporate-experience-to-a-startup/&quot;&gt;How do you sell your corporate experience to a startup?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on November 18, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[#ATHLETE? Not quite, but I did run the marathon.]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/athlete-not-quite-but-i-did-run-the-marathon/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/athlete-not-quite-but-i-did-run-the-marathon</id>
  <published>2011-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2011-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Kurdziel</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>ckurdziel@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I used to hate running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a week and a half ago (yeah, I know this post is late), I had the pleasure of running the 42nd ING NYC Marathon along with a few of my colleagues at &lt;a href=&quot;http://shelby.tv&quot;&gt;Shelby.tv&lt;/a&gt; and a few classmates at Cornell.  Aside from the obvious &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/42_(number)#The_Hitchhiker.27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy&quot;&gt;numerical significance&lt;/a&gt; of the event, my 26.2 mile journey gave me a chance to think about what the whole experience of training, fundraising and running has done for me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ludjy87eB71qaedq5.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike a few of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://reecepacheco.com/post/10733513796/ok-heres-episode-2-from-last-week-we-got-a&quot;&gt;compadres&lt;/a&gt; at Shelby, I&amp;#8217;ve never considered myself much of an athlete. I didn&amp;#8217;t have a time goal for the marathon - instead my focus was on running the entire 26.2 miles and making it across the finish line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the day, I&amp;#8217;m incredibly grateful that my legs held out and that I was able to finish the race.  Though my time wasn&amp;#8217;t the best, I&amp;#8217;m definitely proud of the fact that my splits actually got faster during each subsequent mile.  Some more experienced marathoners have told me that this is a pretty tough thing to do, so I guess that means I did something right. As many who have run marathons will tell you, the last six miles are brutal (at any pace) and in that final stretch, I discovered I had more mental fortitude than I thought to &lt;a href=&quot;http://chriskurdziel.com/2011/10/25/love-this-pic-as-someone-who-works-for-a-startup-and-is-running-the-marathon-lets-hope-i-finish-i-agreearainertwith-the-nyc-marathon-a-few-weeks-away-november-6th-people-make-sure-you-get-out-there-and.html&quot;&gt;finish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the mental (and obvious physical) benefits of running a marathon, I was lucky enough to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamintraining.org/&quot;&gt;Team in Training program&lt;/a&gt;, which is an extension of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lls.org/&quot;&gt;Leukemia and Lymphoma society&lt;/a&gt;. My grandfather died from lymphoplasmactic lymphoma a few years ago and I wanted to honor his memory and support a cause that is dear to my heart.  There were definitely a few moments during the run on Sunday when I spent a lot of time reflecting on how lucky I am to be in good health and to be able to run such an amazing race.  Thanks to everyone - family, friends and others - who took the time to support me in raising money for this cause.  I can&amp;#8217;t thank you enough - you helped &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.teamintraining.org/nyc/nyc11/bigred&quot;&gt;our team become the top fundraising family &amp;amp; friends team in the NYC chapter for Team in Training&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of my run, I ran into a bunch of people I met in NY tech this summer, family, friends and a few thousand new faces as well. Much like my experience in NY tech, I&amp;#8217;ve found that my level of success and happiness is really tightly coupled with the awesome people I surround myself with.  With that in mind, thanks to everyone in NYC for coming out and supporting all of the runners.  Never thought I&amp;#8217;d say this&amp;#8230;but&amp;#8230;I don&amp;#8217;t think this was my last marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS - If you&amp;#8217;re interested in donating to my Team in Training campaign (you still can!), check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.teamintraining.org/nyc/nyc11/ckurdzivgz&quot;&gt;donation page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/athlete-not-quite-but-i-did-run-the-marathon/&quot;&gt;#ATHLETE? Not quite, but I did run the marathon.&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Chris Kurdziel at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;ChrisKurdziel.com&lt;/a&gt; on November 17, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
