<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-22T13:35:16-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ChrisKurdziel.com</title><subtitle>If you wish to make an apple pie from scratch, you must first write a blog post about it on the internet.</subtitle><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><entry><title type="html">Shelby for iPad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/03/22/shelby-ipad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shelby for iPad" /><published>2014-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2014-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2014/03/22/shelby-ipad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2014/03/22/shelby-ipad.html">&lt;p&gt;Today we’re releasing a brand new iPad app to complement our existing iPhone app and web app. We’ve worked really hard on refining Shelby and I’m proud to say this is the best app we’ve ever built. So what sets it apart from the other stuff we’ve built and the rest of the video apps on the App Store? Here’s my take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-choose-your-own-adventure&quot;&gt;Getting started: choose your own adventure.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After opening the app, I’m greeted with two choices: Get Started or Login. If I’m a first-time Shelby user, I choose “Get started.” The title screen animates away, revealing an introduction, a selection of video to watch, and channels to follow. I’m also able to connect Facebook here or hold off until I’ve had a chance to use the app further.
This experience feels a bit like a “choose your own adventure” — I need to add video to my stream, but there are a few ways to do it. A lot of times user onboarding in apps feels very heavy handed—Flipboard requires an email address before they let you see any content—like I’m being pushed through a funnel toward something I’m not sure if I want, instead of letting me explore a magical world with a few helpful tips along the way. The approach we took here is much lighter weight and in keeping with more modern mobile approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shelby.tv, an iPad app to help you discover new videos, no longer requires signups: &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/MEwrhElpNe&quot;&gt;http://t.co/MEwrhElpNe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mashable (@mashable) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mashable/statuses/447098614725509120&quot;&gt;March 21, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked out a few of the publishers in the channels section and followed the ones I tend to keep up with on a regular basis, like Vice and the NY Times. There’s a pretty good mixture of stuff in fashion, food, tech, news and more, but I’d love to see more here and also be able to search for other providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of Channels in the app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/ipad-Shelby-channels.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shelby Channels on iPad&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-fastest-video-player-on-ios-ive-ever-experienced&quot;&gt;The fastest video player on iOS I’ve ever experienced.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I watched a few videos and tried out the swipe-able video player, which we’ve put a lot of time into. It’s really fast — swipe up or down over the player, and the video changes to the corresponding one in the stream. On my home wifi connection (standard Time Warner Cable) I don’t experience any delays due to buffering, so changing videos here is way faster than even changing the channel on my TV.
So far I’ve had a pretty cool experience but I haven’t yet formally registered for Shelby. The experience is somewhat personalized (I’ve followed channels I’m interested in) and I’m still seeing recommendations in my stream. I still want a little more personalization, and I think it’s pretty clear I can get that by connecting Facebook or signing up. I’ve seen a few “sign up” banners in different parts of the app and I clicked one and signed up with my Facebook account. After confirming a few quick profile details and my bio, I’m back to watching video. Pretty simple and painless, and all of my prior work (following channels, etc) has been brought over to my account, so I don’t need to start again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I really wish more apps took this approach with signup.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relevant-content-every-day&quot;&gt;Relevant content every day.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the app every day over coffee in the morning and after dinner in the evening. Each time I open it, I find interesting video. These videos are from a different place each time: sometimes I find the community sharing interesting stuff (found in Explore), sometimes I find the recommendations from Shelby particularly impressive (mostly because they were things I would never search for or come across), and other times I just enjoy the vanilla stuff from TED and the other channels I follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;straightforward-beautiful-design&quot;&gt;Straightforward, beautiful design.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m really glad we kept the design simple. I can focus more on video and less on how the hell I’m supposed to work the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the app feels simple and fun to use whether I’m on the couch connected to AppleTV catching up on the day’s video or showing a friend a video that I’ve discovered lately. So what is the app missing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want even more context around videos.&lt;/strong&gt; What haven’t my friends seen yet? What’s trending nearby? If I’m on the couch, I want videos that are longer. If I’m on my phone in the elevator, I want quick 1 minute videos to watch. We’re thinking a lot about what information is relevant and how/when to present it to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better controls for improving the quality of my stream and facilitating discovery.&lt;/strong&gt; Provided you have a strong social graph and like the video sources we’ve integrated into the app so far, Shelby is a pretty strong video experience. The problem is that everyone has a unique taste fingerprint and while our recommendations do a good job of surfacing new and interesting videos, they take some time to work. I’d love to see more options to build a stream that’s relevant to my interests even before I sign up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I can’t completely give away our roadmap, I can say that the stuff in the list above is part of how we’re thinking about where to take Shelby next. If you’re interested in learning more, shoot me an email at chris[at]shelby.tv. I’d love to chat.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><summary type="html">Today we’re releasing a brand new iPad app to complement our existing iPhone app and web app. We’ve worked really hard on refining Shelby and I’m proud to say this is the best app we’ve ever built. So what sets it apart from the other stuff we’ve built and the rest of the video apps on the App Store? Here’s my take.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Open Letter to TV Manufacturers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/02/06/open-letter-tv-manufacturers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Open Letter to TV Manufacturers" /><published>2014-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2014-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2014/02/06/open-letter-tv-manufacturers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2014/02/06/open-letter-tv-manufacturers.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear TV Manufacturers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile ecosystem &lt;a href=&quot;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2014/1/28/ecosystem-maths&quot;&gt;maths&lt;/a&gt; show that we’re living in an Android and iOS world. The numbers here are huge, and there’s no question these two platforms are going to dominate for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on TV, we’re in the “pre-iPhone world” — this fragmented ecosystem looks/feels a lot like mobile before iOS/Android. &lt;strong&gt;But that doesn’t mean “create an totally new App Store” is the best way forward&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://readwrite.com/2014/01/27/smart-tv-smartphones-televisions&quot;&gt;others agree&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People expect all their services on multiple devices, and they’re choosing mobile before other devices in &lt;a href=&quot;http://ben-evans.com/benedictevans/2014/1/28/ecosystem-maths&quot;&gt;overwhelming numbers&lt;/a&gt;. Expecting that every type of device should have its own separate app platform is kind of crazy. Two of my devices already share the same app store (my tablet and my Phone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it. You can’t just be a “glass manufacturer” lest your margins become as thin as your displays. So you build Apps for your TV or invest in putting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/ces-2014/2014/1/6/5282348/lg-at-ces-2014&quot;&gt;Palm OS on TVs&lt;/a&gt;, and claim TVs as “smart!” But, what really makes a device smart? Is it the fact that you can run apps on it, or the fact that it has sensors and all kinds of other stuff in it that let it interact with the world around it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####You can learn from what happened in the mobile ecosystem here: the phone isn’t just a phone with an App Store, it’s a collection of sensors and different pieces of hardware that Apple and Google give people access to through their developer ecosytems. Your screens have to appeal to the same developer ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AppleTV will keep updating — it will play very nicely with iOS (and probably less nicely with Android). Google already has Chromecast and &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrome.blogspot.com/2014/02/chromecast-is-now-open-to-developers.html&quot;&gt;just released an open SDK&lt;/a&gt; that works nicely with iOS &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Android. These are companies that know how to create and foster developer ecosystems around their products already, and they’re starting to do it with TVs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, TV manufacturers, you and Apple are different companies, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://stratechery.com/2014/two-bears-revisited/&quot;&gt;Ben Thompson has pointed out&lt;/a&gt;. You’ve attempted to achieve software differentiation with software based “App Store” approach, but part of what makes an App Store compelling is access to hardware and freedom for developers to build interesting things. Right now, TV App Stores don’t have this, so they’re nothing more than a facade for apps that have all been built for other types of screens and ported to TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful app stores are the result of robust developer tools and strong access to hardware components, not the other way around. Instead of focusing on ramming “Apps” for TV down our throats, focus on building tools that let mobile developers take advantage of your screens to do really neat things, and provide a simple and clean user experience on TV. You’re better at making TVs than both Google and Apple. Don’t just build stuff into TVs that make the picture better — think outside the box and make the experience better. Add some sensors, cameras and other hardware that make your products stand out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of sensors? Here are some ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microphone&lt;/strong&gt; — Voice input is the remote that most people have. Not an ideal solution for all use cases, but nice to have as an option. Could also be used for automatic volume control, communication apps, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrared Camera&lt;/strong&gt; — to be used as a proximity sensor (a-la Kinect). And don’t just give me access to the raw data, how about a well documented SDK that developers can actually use in interesting ways?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camera&lt;/strong&gt; — obvious applications are video conferencing, but my guess is that this could open up other cool possibilities too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bluetooth 4.0/LE&lt;/strong&gt; — Don’t want to sound too much like my friend Steve Cheney here, but iBeacon and Bluetooth LE are a big deal, and not just in local commerce. Let developers play with this stuff in the household, too. Imagine a TV that turns on intelligently when mobile devices are nearby and that plays content related to the person/people nearby (based on mobile device(s)). Add another person/device to the mix, and your content lineup changes accordingly. Change rooms and the TV changes in the next room as you move around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WiFi Router/Repeater&lt;/strong&gt; — Integrating this with a TV eliminates the need to enter your WiFi password or connect a bunch of cords. It’s clean and it all works out of the box!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Antennae&lt;/strong&gt; — there’s no reason over the air content should require you to buy add-on antennas, and there’s tons of free content available over the air you can unlock for people so that TVs become truly “Plug and Play.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And at the software level, access to the following would be cool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Onscreen notifications&lt;/strong&gt; — push from mobile OR push from TV apps. Any mobile app company would want to experiment with this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A “queue” of “video objects” or “collections of video objects” to watch.&lt;/strong&gt; Work with Netflix, Hulu, Shelby (shameless plug!) and others to let users send their content to this queue so you have the one true Instapaper for video.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask developers what they want!&lt;/strong&gt; Get out there and build a relationship with the developer ecosystem and listen to their feedback. There are tons of interesting startups. Work with them to find the components they want access to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Samsung, LG, Vizio and Sony, do you have what it takes to invest in this stuff? It’s not too late, but it might be if you wait any longer. Be bold. Start now. By the time Apple and Google figure out how to launch integrated TV hardware themselves, you’ll have a fighting chance. And as consumers, we’ll all be better off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS — I don’t have all the answers, so if you agree or disagree, leave a comment and let me know what you think! I would love for this to be an open discussion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><summary type="html">Dear TV Manufacturers,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lessons from Launching a Product on my Honeymoon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/12/03/launching-honeymoon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons from Launching a Product on my Honeymoon" /><published>2013-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/12/03/launching-honeymoon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/12/03/launching-honeymoon.html">&lt;p&gt;This past month, we shipped the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://shl.by/iphone&quot;&gt;Shelby.tv iPhone app&lt;/a&gt; to the world. It was the culmination of over a year’s worth of work after we &lt;a href=&quot;http://shelby.tv/blog/post/26927127539/new-shelby-shutdown&quot;&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; our product over a year ago to rebuild it from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Shelby’s product guy, I was responsible for making sure that the team shipped a quality product on a date that made sense for the company. There was only one problem — during our optimal launch week I was supposed to be on my honeymoon. It turns out that didn’t matter, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went on my honeymoon and we still had a great launch (you can read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/11/14/like-the-legend-of-the-phoenix-all-ends-with-video-discovery/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). And the team didn’t really miss me because we were proactive about preparing in the right ways from the beginning. After some reflection, here are the reasons why I think this is the case:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Everyone is an owner
Everyone on our team is good at something different. We each had a unique role to play in launch and as a result could each own different pieces of making launch a success. Trusting each team member to execute and own their respective pieces of launch was important. Had all the pieces had the same person owning them, we would have had a single point of failure during launch week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Time spent staying organized = less time spent executing
Trello is a fantastic piece of software. We use it everyday for staying on top of product work and planning what’s next. Sometimes, as we learned, a good old fashioned spreadsheet does a great job, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our launch, we kept a spreadsheet detailing what needed to happen at virtually every part of the company for each week prior to launch. Every Monday AM and Friday PM, we’d review the spreadsheet as a team to make sure we were leaving no stone unturned (much like we also review Trello).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days before launch, the team built an even more detailed spreadsheet that acted as an hour-by-hour script for launch day. Everyone contributed and cranked through it together on launch day to make sure everything was done in the right order and on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/Shelby-team-working.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The team cranking through work on launch day.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Practice like you play
Ultimately, we instituted a lot of good practices shipping product prior to our iOS launch by slowly transitioning from our closed beta on the web to an open beta on the web. Carrying over these habits toward launch wasn’t much more than a natural extension of our day-to-day work. As a result, we didn’t put launch on a pedestal and were able to trust the rhythm we had already developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Lessons for Product Managers
I have a natural tendency to be a kind of self-deprecating guy,so at first I was a little bummed that the team had such a great launch without me. How much difference do I make at Shelby if the team doesn’t miss me when I’m gone for our most critical event in the past year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking about it a little more,I think this might be an indication that I’m actually pretty good at my job. Yes, a good product leader needs to be there to drive things forward, but product managers can only do so much (we’re not “managers” in the traditional HR sense). The manager in the “product manager” moniker refers to managing the product, not people, and I think it’s really important for PMs to remember this as they do their job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a PM, you are a leader who tries to set the course for product direction. With the right communication and organization tools in place, the team will move towards a common goal without you micromanaging them or cracking a whip. The hard work to do that happens well before any big launch event, so set your course early, and focus on building something sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still learning and I’d love to know what you think of this post and my approach, so if you’re a product person, let me know what you think. I’ll keep this post updated with comments and questions, so feel free to chime in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><summary type="html">This past month, we shipped the new Shelby.tv iPhone app to the world. It was the culmination of over a year’s worth of work after we shut down our product over a year ago to rebuild it from the ground up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wireframing for Noobs (MBAs too!)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/04/04/product-thursday-wireframing-for-noobs-mbas-too.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wireframing for Noobs (MBAs too!)" /><published>2013-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/04/04/product-thursday-wireframing-for-noobs-mbas-too</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/04/04/product-thursday-wireframing-for-noobs-mbas-too.html">&lt;p&gt;One of the longstanding jokes in business school is that MBAs think in PowerPoint. In the startup world, people don&amp;#8217;t often think in PowerPoint - they think in code.  So what&amp;#8217;s the easiest way to bridge that gap?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t try and be something you&amp;#8217;re not (unless you actually want to learn how to code). Instead, use the skills you have/are good at and put them to good use. Think you&amp;#8217;ve got a great idea for a product but can&amp;#8217;t build it with code? Build it with PowerPoint or Keynote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clickable prototypes save a ton of time in the design process and you can get your ideas in front of people quickly to test whether or not they&amp;#8217;re valid. Keynote works on iPads too, so if you&amp;#8217;re looking to build a mobile app, you can do it in Keynote AND test it on iPads with real users.  I&amp;#8217;ve been doing this lately and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more excuses. &lt;a href=&quot;http://reecepacheco.com/post/29701849789/the-end-product-and-a-core-part-of-shelbys&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JFBI&lt;/a&gt;, even if it is in Keynote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="clickable prototypes" /><category term="mvp" /><category term="Product Thursdays" /><category term="Product Management" /><summary type="html">One of the longstanding jokes in business school is that MBAs think in PowerPoint. In the startup world, people don&amp;#8217;t often think in PowerPoint - they think in code.  So what&amp;#8217;s the easiest way to bridge that gap? Don&amp;#8217;t try and be something you&amp;#8217;re not (unless you actually want to learn how to code). Instead, use the skills you have/are good at and put them to good use. Think you&amp;#8217;ve got a great idea for a product but can&amp;#8217;t build it with code? Build it with PowerPoint or Keynote. Clickable prototypes save a ton of time in the design process and you can get your ideas in front of people quickly to test whether or not they&amp;#8217;re valid. Keynote works on iPads too, so if you&amp;#8217;re looking to build a mobile app, you can do it in Keynote AND test it on iPads with real users.  I&amp;#8217;ve been doing this lately and I love it. No more excuses. JFBI, even if it is in Keynote.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">House of Cards: The Content Wars Are A Game of Thrones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/04/02/house-of-cards-the-content-wars-are-a-game-of-thrones.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="House of Cards: The Content Wars Are A Game of Thrones" /><published>2013-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/04/02/house-of-cards-the-content-wars-are-a-game-of-thrones</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/04/02/house-of-cards-the-content-wars-are-a-game-of-thrones.html">&lt;p&gt;House of Cards has gotten a ton of attention lately for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;It&amp;#8217;s an awesome show (though I haven&amp;#8217;t seen it yet)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;All episodes were delivered at the same time (to satisfy binge viewers)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;It&amp;#8217;s another major step for Netflix in delivering unique content to keep viewers locked into their model&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is this model smart?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content providers can use exclusive content to be valuable &amp;amp; differentiate themselves from competitors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Netflix has already done this with Lilyhammer.  They&amp;#8217;ve also continued tapping into&lt;span&gt; &quot;binge viewing&quot; behavior in an organized way.  Although it&amp;#8217;s unclear what the biggest benefits of that behavior will be quite yet, they&amp;#8217;re learning something valuable by being a first mover here. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People want access to content without restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and aside from being the only place to access it, Netflix&amp;#8217;s distribution models is working for consumers with a &amp;#8220;watch where you want, when you want&quot; mindset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;What are the downsides of this model?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s really expensive and only works for top-quality content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Because its so expensive to do it this way (and therefore the costs of failure are high), it only works for top caliber content and therefore isn&amp;#8217;t something that will be the only way things are done. It&amp;#8217;s why &amp;#8220;pilots&quot; exist in TV - see if the audience likes it and then sink more money into it. Episodic content that follows this model also has a benefit of giving viewers a reason to come back to a service. In that sense I think we&amp;#8217;ll see these models mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Piracy is still going to be a big issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; If you don&amp;#8217;t subscribe to Netflix or the service, there&amp;#8217;s no way to get the content except pirating it. That&amp;#8217;s part of the reason Game of Thrones was pirated a ton (and consequently was so successful). Many of the dynamics in &lt;a href=&quot;http://liisten.com/strategy-for-releasing-music-online&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; on the music industry could also apply to video content. We still haven&amp;#8217;t seen a producer of content fully embrace the piracy engine to positive effect yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does this all mean for the people playing this &amp;#8220;game of thrones&quot; in the content landscape?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The implications of all of this are good for startups - Americans watch over 5 hours a day of content and not all of it is that &amp;#8220;top notch&quot; stuff like House of Cards or Game of Thrones. Startups don&amp;#8217;t need to unseat that &amp;#8220;top value&quot; content quite yet - they can let this game of thrones happen and focus more on the Torso of TV (&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2012/06/06/the-power-of-torso-tv-why-media-is-racing-to-the-middle/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;read Suster&amp;#8217;s post if you haven&amp;#8217;t&lt;/a&gt;) and create a ton of value around providing meaningful context and discovery for the rest of the video landscape.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="house of cards" /><category term="game of thrones" /><category term="content wars" /><category term="netflix" /><category term="piracy" /><category term="torso tv" /><category term="media" /><category term="tech" /><category term="linkbait titles" /><summary type="html">House of Cards has gotten a ton of attention lately for a few reasons: It&amp;#8217;s an awesome show (though I haven&amp;#8217;t seen it yet) All episodes were delivered at the same time (to satisfy binge viewers) It&amp;#8217;s another major step for Netflix in delivering unique content to keep viewers locked into their model Why is this model smart? Content providers can use exclusive content to be valuable &amp;amp; differentiate themselves from competitors. Netflix has already done this with Lilyhammer.  They&amp;#8217;ve also continued tapping into &quot;binge viewing&quot; behavior in an organized way.  Although it&amp;#8217;s unclear what the biggest benefits of that behavior will be quite yet, they&amp;#8217;re learning something valuable by being a first mover here. People want access to content without restrictions and aside from being the only place to access it, Netflix&amp;#8217;s distribution models is working for consumers with a &amp;#8220;watch where you want, when you want&quot; mindset. What are the downsides of this model? It&amp;#8217;s really expensive and only works for top-quality content. Because its so expensive to do it this way (and therefore the costs of failure are high), it only works for top caliber content and therefore isn&amp;#8217;t something that will be the only way things are done. It&amp;#8217;s why &amp;#8220;pilots&quot; exist in TV - see if the audience likes it and then sink more money into it. Episodic content that follows this model also has a benefit of giving viewers a reason to come back to a service. In that sense I think we&amp;#8217;ll see these models mix. Piracy is still going to be a big issue. If you don&amp;#8217;t subscribe to Netflix or the service, there&amp;#8217;s no way to get the content except pirating it. That&amp;#8217;s part of the reason Game of Thrones was pirated a ton (and consequently was so successful). Many of the dynamics in this post on the music industry could also apply to video content. We still haven&amp;#8217;t seen a producer of content fully embrace the piracy engine to positive effect yet. What does this all mean for the people playing this &amp;#8220;game of thrones&quot; in the content landscape? The implications of all of this are good for startups - Americans watch over 5 hours a day of content and not all of it is that &amp;#8220;top notch&quot; stuff like House of Cards or Game of Thrones. Startups don&amp;#8217;t need to unseat that &amp;#8220;top value&quot; content quite yet - they can let this game of thrones happen and focus more on the Torso of TV (read Suster&amp;#8217;s post if you haven&amp;#8217;t) and create a ton of value around providing meaningful context and discovery for the rest of the video landscape.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Killing Google Reader</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/03/14/product-thursday-killing-google-reader.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Killing Google Reader" /><published>2013-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/03/14/product-thursday-killing-google-reader</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/03/14/product-thursday-killing-google-reader.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Google &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;announced they&amp;#8217;re killing Reader&lt;/a&gt;, one of their most beloved (if my Twitter stream is to be believed) products in their portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a few different apps/sites to keep up with the news. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Google Reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reeder (Google Reader interface for iOS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instapaper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;News.Me Daily Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techmeme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hacker News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use each of these services for different reasons, and though I&amp;#8217;ve developed a pretty good flow of how they each fit into my day, I&amp;#8217;ve been longing for a better solution. I really wish that there was a product that tied these things together in one or two apps. What would that product look like? Here&amp;#8217;s a quick stab and what I&amp;#8217;d love to see for my two common use cases (daily &amp;#8220;must reads&quot; &amp;amp; weekly &amp;#8220;discovery&quot; reading):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Must Read: My Daily Use Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep/read a curated list of the stuff I absolutely want to see on a regular basis anytime there are updates. This is the stuff I want to read no matter what and it&amp;#8217;s mostly blogs of people who I engage with on a regular basis. (It&amp;#8217;s what Google Reader became for me.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give me an idea of top posts in my social network. The news.me email from the Digg team does a good job of giving me stuff that I may have missed or not seen that&amp;#8217;s highly relevant. Generally only 3-5 of these articles are really necessary to get an idea of what&amp;#8217;s relevant in my network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there isn&amp;#8217;t enough content on a daily basis, then don&amp;#8217;t show me more. Let me get a few minutes of my day back.  This is a problem a lot of apps don&amp;#8217;t consider because they&amp;#8217;re looking for more engagement (which often times = shoving more content in front of you).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discover: My Weekly/When I Have Time Use Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once I&amp;#8217;m done with the daily read, open the floodgates and give me some variety. This could be seeded with content, topics and things I&amp;#8217;ve shown an interest in (like Zite) or it could be powered by people I&amp;#8217;m connected to socially. Ideally it&amp;#8217;s a mix of all of the above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I&amp;#8217;ve saved articles for later, show me these articles before letting me run wild exploring the ends of the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hard part here is figuring out how to combine these use cases in an app. Part of the power is in keeping them separate: the problem with apps like Zite is that I never know if I missed an article from a &amp;#8220;must read&quot; site and I don&amp;#8217;t have an interest in discovering new tangental content unless I&amp;#8217;ve finished the stuff that I know is relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one of the big problems with these weekly apps is that I often forget to go back to them on a regular basis, and they often have content in them that I&amp;#8217;ve already seen or seen elsewhere.  There&amp;#8217;s a strong case for a reading app that unifies these two use cases or at least is aware of what&amp;#8217;s been consumed in the other app so that the probability of duplicates is reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closest thing I&amp;#8217;ve found to this approach is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedafever.com/&quot;&gt;Fever&lt;/a&gt;. It combines &amp;#8220;kindling&quot; (your daily must-reads) with &amp;#8220;sparks&quot; (the rest of the content you are interested in) to give you a smart reading experience.  The only problem? No iOS apps and it&amp;#8217;s self-hosted. :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone else have other ideas out there? Seems that there are a ton of companies tackling this problem but no one has really hit the nail on the head yet (for me).  I&amp;#8217;ve tried Prismatic and while I think the content it surfaces is pretty solid, I find the UX, scrolling and lack of Instapaper support absolutely maddening. Hopefully &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.digg.com/post/45355701332/were-building-a-reader&quot;&gt;Digg&lt;/a&gt; (or someone else) does it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I also realize this problem is completely non-trivial to solve, that my usage pattern is probably pretty niche and that this is not something I can really pretend to solve in a blog post. Flame away. :)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="Product Thursdays" /><category term="google reader" /><category term="reader" /><category term="rss" /><summary type="html">Yesterday, Google announced they&amp;#8217;re killing Reader, one of their most beloved (if my Twitter stream is to be believed) products in their portfolio. I use a few different apps/sites to keep up with the news. Here they are: Google Reader Reeder (Google Reader interface for iOS) Instapaper Zite News.Me Daily Email Twitter Techmeme Hacker News I use each of these services for different reasons, and though I&amp;#8217;ve developed a pretty good flow of how they each fit into my day, I&amp;#8217;ve been longing for a better solution. I really wish that there was a product that tied these things together in one or two apps. What would that product look like? Here&amp;#8217;s a quick stab and what I&amp;#8217;d love to see for my two common use cases (daily &amp;#8220;must reads&quot; &amp;amp; weekly &amp;#8220;discovery&quot; reading): Must Read: My Daily Use Case Keep/read a curated list of the stuff I absolutely want to see on a regular basis anytime there are updates. This is the stuff I want to read no matter what and it&amp;#8217;s mostly blogs of people who I engage with on a regular basis. (It&amp;#8217;s what Google Reader became for me.) Give me an idea of top posts in my social network. The news.me email from the Digg team does a good job of giving me stuff that I may have missed or not seen that&amp;#8217;s highly relevant. Generally only 3-5 of these articles are really necessary to get an idea of what&amp;#8217;s relevant in my network. If there isn&amp;#8217;t enough content on a daily basis, then don&amp;#8217;t show me more. Let me get a few minutes of my day back.  This is a problem a lot of apps don&amp;#8217;t consider because they&amp;#8217;re looking for more engagement (which often times = shoving more content in front of you). Discover: My Weekly/When I Have Time Use Case Once I&amp;#8217;m done with the daily read, open the floodgates and give me some variety. This could be seeded with content, topics and things I&amp;#8217;ve shown an interest in (like Zite) or it could be powered by people I&amp;#8217;m connected to socially. Ideally it&amp;#8217;s a mix of all of the above. If I&amp;#8217;ve saved articles for later, show me these articles before letting me run wild exploring the ends of the internet. The hard part here is figuring out how to combine these use cases in an app. Part of the power is in keeping them separate: the problem with apps like Zite is that I never know if I missed an article from a &amp;#8220;must read&quot; site and I don&amp;#8217;t have an interest in discovering new tangental content unless I&amp;#8217;ve finished the stuff that I know is relevant. However, one of the big problems with these weekly apps is that I often forget to go back to them on a regular basis, and they often have content in them that I&amp;#8217;ve already seen or seen elsewhere.  There&amp;#8217;s a strong case for a reading app that unifies these two use cases or at least is aware of what&amp;#8217;s been consumed in the other app so that the probability of duplicates is reduced. The closest thing I&amp;#8217;ve found to this approach is called Fever. It combines &amp;#8220;kindling&quot; (your daily must-reads) with &amp;#8220;sparks&quot; (the rest of the content you are interested in) to give you a smart reading experience.  The only problem? No iOS apps and it&amp;#8217;s self-hosted. :/ Anyone else have other ideas out there? Seems that there are a ton of companies tackling this problem but no one has really hit the nail on the head yet (for me).  I&amp;#8217;ve tried Prismatic and while I think the content it surfaces is pretty solid, I find the UX, scrolling and lack of Instapaper support absolutely maddening. Hopefully Digg (or someone else) does it right. Note: I also realize this problem is completely non-trivial to solve, that my usage pattern is probably pretty niche and that this is not something I can really pretend to solve in a blog post. Flame away. :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on Mailbox</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/14/product-thursday-thoughts-on-mailbox.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on Mailbox" /><published>2013-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/14/product-thursday-thoughts-on-mailbox</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/14/product-thursday-thoughts-on-mailbox.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/ea130ea588877bbca37dac8458fa7be2/tumblr_inline_mi844pJWBL1qz4rgp.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Over the past week I&amp;#8217;ve been playing with Mailbox, so I figured it might be a good candidate for my first product review on product thursday.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main assumption behind Mailbox is that most people tend to view their inbox as a to-do list.  Though I&amp;#8217;ve tried to shed that assumption in my own use of Gmail, it&amp;#8217;s been hard. Mailbox is a welcome addition and really reduces the need for me to spend time on actively managing an inbox of actionable email.  Every part of the app is designed to get you to inbox zero, so those who want more functionality in their email might feel a bit limited, but Mailbox is awesome for staying on top of email and following up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of my favorite details in the app (barring the obvious ones)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you&amp;#8217;ve cleared your inbox each day, you get a beautiful, relaxing image that is different every day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;#8217;s a nice little touch that feels like a little &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot;reward&quot; each time you hit inbox zero.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changing send-from address popup is easier to use than Apple Mail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;#8217;s a list of email addresses to pick from that requires a simple tap instead of a swipe and a tap like Apple&amp;#8217;s wheel selector does. I imagine Apple&amp;#8217;s solution works better for those who have a ton of addresses, but I only have 3 I actively check so it&amp;#8217;s a nice change.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Threading of messages is handled really elegantly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Gone are the days of tapping into a thread on Apple Mail and then choosing which message you want to see. Instead, messages all load inline and appear collapsed and greyed out if they&amp;#8217;re already read (much like Gmail&amp;#8217;s web interface)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inline/focused replies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;  I find the design of the reply/new message box to be limiting in a really good way.  Because the box doesn&amp;#8217;t give me the entire screen to write a lengthy response, my emails are becoming shorter and more to the point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tasteful use of gestures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;#8217;s a lot of debate about whether or not Clear&amp;#8217;s UX is ideal, but I love it.  Mailbox&amp;#8217;s gestures are built around very quick/easy actions for each email: archive (short swipe right), view later (short swipe left), add to list (long swipe left), and delete (long swipe right).  These have been really easy to pick up and the UI does a great job of making sure you don&amp;#8217;t make any mistakes and accidentally delete things when you wanted to archive them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And my least favorite parts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t change reply-from address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; like you can in Apple Mail (I do this a lot for mail that people send to my Cornell or Shelby addresses that I want to be directed to my Gmail account).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No easy way to find/search filters in Gmail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; At this point I don&amp;#8217;t really find myself missing this a ton, but it&amp;#8217;d be a nice to have.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push notifications are a bit wonky.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; If you have filters in Gmail which are set up to move mail out of your inbox, Mailbox may still badge the app that you have mail. This &amp;#8220;false positive&quot; can be a little frustrating especially if you&amp;#8217;re compulsive about keeping notifications to a minimum on iOS, but I imagine it will get better with time. This is likely one of the reasons they&amp;#8217;re letting people into the app on a rolling basis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No iPad experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Desktop Gmail works pretty well in conjunction with Mailbox, but I&amp;#8217;ve found managing email on my iPad just isn&amp;#8217;t fun anymore. Gimme that iPad app!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;#8217;s about it - not sure how helpful/comprehensive this review is, but hopefully it&amp;#8217;s useful to those that are wondering whether Mailbox is worth the wait (I think it is)!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="mailbox" /><category term="ios" /><category term="Product Thursdays" /><category term="product" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minimum Viable Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/07/product-thursday-minimum-viable-design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minimum Viable Design" /><published>2013-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-02-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/02/07/product-thursday-minimum-viable-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/02/07/product-thursday-minimum-viable-design.html">&lt;p&gt;Lots of startups (especially those in NYC) spend a ton of time on visual design and making sure that the look and feel of their product is close to perfect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While my obsessive tendencies often encourage me to consider every design option presented, I&amp;#8217;ve had to remember that too much attention to design can often get in the way of moving a product forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re a startup trying to iterate quickly, understand your customer base and think about things as an MVP, there are times when it&amp;#8217;s smart to eschew design for shipping product (provided it doesn&amp;#8217;t cripple functionality). That extra bit of design/attention to detail can be helpful, for sure, but a good product person should understand when that matters and when it doesn&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/a23b6d525e8c82a422ac8ef96dfc05c7/tumblr_inline_mi0rezkXtc1qz4rgp.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="Product Thursdays" /><category term="product" /><category term="design" /><category term="lean startup" /><category term="minimum viable design" /><category term="MVP" /><summary type="html">Lots of startups (especially those in NYC) spend a ton of time on visual design and making sure that the look and feel of their product is close to perfect.  While my obsessive tendencies often encourage me to consider every design option presented, I&amp;#8217;ve had to remember that too much attention to design can often get in the way of moving a product forward. If you&amp;#8217;re a startup trying to iterate quickly, understand your customer base and think about things as an MVP, there are times when it&amp;#8217;s smart to eschew design for shipping product (provided it doesn&amp;#8217;t cripple functionality). That extra bit of design/attention to detail can be helpful, for sure, but a good product person should understand when that matters and when it doesn&amp;#8217;t.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“WTF is UX?”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/01/31/product-thursday-wtf-is-ux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;WTF is UX?&quot;" /><published>2013-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-01-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/01/31/product-thursday-wtf-is-ux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/01/31/product-thursday-wtf-is-ux.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/a0896f633e9517394d056d493453124d/tumblr_inline_mhiaoj0usO1qz4rgp.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a great post about UX on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcodesign.com/1671735/infographic-the-intricate-anatomy-of-ux-design&quot;&gt;Fast.co Design&lt;/a&gt; today and it includes the infographic above. The overall point is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To think any designer could be an expert in each of these circles is sheer absurdity, but to recognize that &lt;strong&gt;every end user is an expert&lt;/strong&gt; in each of these circles is highly important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I&amp;#8217;d worked alongside product teams before entering the New York startup community, I&amp;#8217;m not ashamed to admit that I never really heard the term &amp;#8220;UX&quot; used much. I could probably crack a joke about how that&amp;#8217;s unexpected for people who work in big companies that develop enterprise healthcare IT applications, but I&amp;#8217;ll refrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a bit of a n00b on the design front, it took me a while to appreciate the subtleties of these different areas of design. Depending on what you&amp;#8217;re building, each area has a different level of importance, but together they all form something that&amp;#8217;s the cornerstone of your product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While there are many days when I wish I had more formal education on the tenets of good user experience or interaction design, I think it&amp;#8217;s good to remember that no matter how much formal education we have, user experience comes down to putting yourself in the shoes of others &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;and asking &amp;#8220;does this work for me?&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This empathetic approach can be helpful in UX decision-making, but it&amp;#8217;s also a characteristic that increases chances of success in the customer support experience and in service industries. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not saying that one has to be empathetic with the customer/user because they&amp;#8217;re always right. On the contrary, the customer may be wrong (and angry!), but their perspective is valid and should be used to gain insight and understanding around the experience. Ultimately, it&amp;#8217;s up to the &amp;#8220;UX&quot; person to translate that perspective into something that is actionable/productive for all parties involved.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="Product Thursdays" /><category term="Product Management" /><category term="product" /><category term="empathy" /><category term="ux" /><summary type="html">There&amp;#8217;s a great post about UX on Fast.co Design today and it includes the infographic above. The overall point is the following: To think any designer could be an expert in each of these circles is sheer absurdity, but to recognize that every end user is an expert in each of these circles is highly important. Though I&amp;#8217;d worked alongside product teams before entering the New York startup community, I&amp;#8217;m not ashamed to admit that I never really heard the term &amp;#8220;UX&quot; used much. I could probably crack a joke about how that&amp;#8217;s unexpected for people who work in big companies that develop enterprise healthcare IT applications, but I&amp;#8217;ll refrain. Being a bit of a n00b on the design front, it took me a while to appreciate the subtleties of these different areas of design. Depending on what you&amp;#8217;re building, each area has a different level of importance, but together they all form something that&amp;#8217;s the cornerstone of your product.  While there are many days when I wish I had more formal education on the tenets of good user experience or interaction design, I think it&amp;#8217;s good to remember that no matter how much formal education we have, user experience comes down to putting yourself in the shoes of others and asking &amp;#8220;does this work for me?&quot; This empathetic approach can be helpful in UX decision-making, but it&amp;#8217;s also a characteristic that increases chances of success in the customer support experience and in service industries. I&amp;#8217;m not saying that one has to be empathetic with the customer/user because they&amp;#8217;re always right. On the contrary, the customer may be wrong (and angry!), but their perspective is valid and should be used to gain insight and understanding around the experience. Ultimately, it&amp;#8217;s up to the &amp;#8220;UX&quot; person to translate that perspective into something that is actionable/productive for all parties involved.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Designing with Emotion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/01/24/product-thursday-designing-with-emotion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing with Emotion" /><published>2013-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2013-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/01/24/product-thursday-designing-with-emotion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/01/24/product-thursday-designing-with-emotion.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://media.tumblr.com/2a55e6fa1b9395b1b7bc6965913e72e7/tumblr_inline_mh5amt0xXq1qaedq5.jpg&quot;/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1937557006/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1937557006&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=chriskurdziel-20&quot;&gt;Designing for Emotion&lt;/a&gt;, which contains a number of interesting examples about how design can be used to evoke emotion. &lt;span&gt;There are a few cool examples in the book, but the one that stood out to me most was Apple&amp;#8217;s implementation of their blinking sleep status indicator. This has been documented before (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freepatentsonline.com/6658577.html&quot;&gt;and patented back in 2002&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;), but if anyone has wondered why their Macbook&amp;#8217;s sleep indicator was strangely comforting it&amp;#8217;s because the pulsating rhythm is based on the respiratory rate of a human (12-20 cycles per minute).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;At Shelby, one of our core values is &quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be human&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&quot; - this applies in the way we carry ourselves in the larger startup community, internally with our team and also in the way we approach building product.  This is a product philosophy that I&amp;#8217;m increasingly taking to heart and one that I think has to be at the center of transformative technology products in slower-moving, low-tech industries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Take healthcare, for example. There are a ton of technology companies building solutions for the healthcare enterprise (I used to work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mckesson.com&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt;), but most are just focused on performing a specific task and not providing enjoyable UX. As Aaron Walter says in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1937557006/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1937557006&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=chriskurdziel-20&quot;&gt;Designing for Emotion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &amp;#8220;certainly we all want to eat edible foods with nutritional value, but we also crave &lt;em&gt;flavor&lt;/em&gt;.&quot; Based on my experience, design of healthcare IT systems has been focused on making products that are &amp;#8220;edible&quot; - they get the job done but they&amp;#8217;re pretty crappy in terms of creating an experience that physicians feel they can&amp;#8217;t live without.  It&amp;#8217;s no surprise to see that adoption of healthcare tech &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationweek.com/healthcare/electronic-medical-records/ehr-adoption-us-remains-the-slow-poke/240142152&quot;&gt;is slow&lt;/a&gt;. I believe there&amp;#8217;s a huge opportunity for better, more human design to help speed the adoption of healthcare tech among a physician population that is short on time and patience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Anyone else have other examples of industries waiting to be transformed by designing with emotion?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Kurdziel</name></author><category term="Product Thursdays" /><category term="product" /><category term="design" /><category term="Shelby" /><category term="be human" /><category term="Healthcare" /><summary type="html">  I just finished reading Designing for Emotion, which contains a number of interesting examples about how design can be used to evoke emotion. There are a few cool examples in the book, but the one that stood out to me most was Apple&amp;#8217;s implementation of their blinking sleep status indicator. This has been documented before (and patented back in 2002), but if anyone has wondered why their Macbook&amp;#8217;s sleep indicator was strangely comforting it&amp;#8217;s because the pulsating rhythm is based on the respiratory rate of a human (12-20 cycles per minute). At Shelby, one of our core values is &quot;be human&quot; - this applies in the way we carry ourselves in the larger startup community, internally with our team and also in the way we approach building product.  This is a product philosophy that I&amp;#8217;m increasingly taking to heart and one that I think has to be at the center of transformative technology products in slower-moving, low-tech industries.   Take healthcare, for example. There are a ton of technology companies building solutions for the healthcare enterprise (I used to work at one), but most are just focused on performing a specific task and not providing enjoyable UX. As Aaron Walter says in Designing for Emotion, &amp;#8220;certainly we all want to eat edible foods with nutritional value, but we also crave flavor.&quot; Based on my experience, design of healthcare IT systems has been focused on making products that are &amp;#8220;edible&quot; - they get the job done but they&amp;#8217;re pretty crappy in terms of creating an experience that physicians feel they can&amp;#8217;t live without.  It&amp;#8217;s no surprise to see that adoption of healthcare tech is slow. I believe there&amp;#8217;s a huge opportunity for better, more human design to help speed the adoption of healthcare tech among a physician population that is short on time and patience. Anyone else have other examples of industries waiting to be transformed by designing with emotion?</summary></entry></feed>